[MUSIC]
[음악]
Okay, now I wanna do one last thing,
이제 저는 가장 마지막 것을 하고 싶습니다.
because it will be just fun, and then we can all be excited.
왜나하면 이것은 그저 재미있을 것이고, 우리는 모두 신나게 될 수 있기 때문이죠.
So what I did here, query on a particular car for a particular image.
제가 여기서 한 것은, 특정 이미지를 위한 특정 자동차에 대한 질의입니다.
Let's create a function that does all of that and we can create anytime I want.
이 모든 것들을 할 수 있는 함수를 만들어보죠. 그리고 우리는 이것을 제가 원할 때 아무때나 만들 수 있습니다.
And so this will be kind
이것은 꽤나
of a fun thing to do.
재미있는 일이 될 것입니다.
So, just for fun,
그저 재미를 위해서
let's create a lambda to find and
가장 가까운 이웃의 이미지들을 찾고 보여줄 수 있는
show nearest neighbor images.
함수를 만들어 보죠.
So, this is a little bit of Python trickery.
이것은 일종의 파이썬의 사기와 같습니다.
We get to play with it together.
우리는 이것들과 함께 작업하게 되죠.
So, we're gonna call this lambda.
우리는 이것을 lambda라고 부를 것입니다.
Find, no, just go directly to show.
찾기 위해, 아니 그저 직접 보여주기 위해서 입니다.
Show_neighbors and
Show_neighbors를 입력하면
this is gonna be a lambda and it's gonna take the index i of the image.
이것은 lambda가 되고 해당 이미지의 인덱스 i를 가져올 것입니다.
And here it is what it's gonna do.
그리고 여기 이것이 바로 그것이 하게 될 일입니다.
It's going to do exactly what we saw.
이것은 우리가 보았던 것과 똑같은 일을 할 것입니다.
So it's gonna get images from IDs, query the nearestneighbor model,
따라서 이것은 ID로부터 이미지들을 가져와서 가장 가까운 이웃 모델에 대해 질의할 것입니다.
but instead of query for car, let's query from image train of i to i plus one.
하지만 자동차에 대한 질의 대신, i부터 i+1까지의 기차의 이미지에 대해 질의해 보죠.
And then we're gonna take the image and we're gonna call .show in it.
그런 다음 우리는 이미지를 가져온 다음 .show를 호출할 것입니다.
This is a crazy long lambda.
이것은 엄청나게 긴 lambda 입니다.
But after we created it, we can do something pretty neat with it.
하지만 이것을 생성하고 난 후 우리는 이것을 가지고 꽤 깔끔한 일을 할 수 있습니다.
So now, I can just call show_neighbors and
이제, 저는 show_neighbors를 호출하고
I give it the index of the car which was eight, and
8이었던 자동차 인덱스 값을 줄 것입니다.
if you scroll down, you'll see those red cars.
스크롤을 내려보시면, 여러분은 이 빨간 자동차들을 볼 수 있을 것입니다.
Really cool.
정말 멋지죠.
Now, we can call show_neighbors with some other image.
이제 우리는 show_neighbors를 다른 이미지들을 사용해서 호출할 수 있습니다.
I actually haven't thought about or played with this, I just made this lambda
저는 실제로 아직 이것들에 대해 생각해보거나 사용해본적이 없습니다. 저는 그저 이 lambda를 만들었을 뿐이죠.
up together, so actually, I haven't, let's just try and run numbers.
일단 숫자들의 실행을 시도해보도록 하죠.
So, how about number 26?
숫자 26은 어떤가요?
So now it's gonna find the neighbors that even know what it is,
이제 이것은 이미 무엇인지 알고 있는 이웃들까지 찾아낼 것입니다.
26 is this car over here.
26은 바료 여기의 자동차입니다.
Actually let me make this a little bigger, so we can all see.
우리 모두가 볼 수 있도록 이것을 좀 더 크게 만들어 보겠습니다.
So show neighbors of 26 is this blue car.
26의 show neighbors는 이 파란색 자동차입니다.
This assigns a few other cars, which is pretty cool.
이것은 다른 자동차들을 배치하는데 매우 멋지죠.
Let's pick some other number, show_neighbors
다른 숫자를 골라보죠. 이 2,000 또는 1222에 대한 이미지들에 대한
of these 2,000 images maybe image 1222.
show_neighbors를 실행합니다.
I actually don't know what that would be, but now we can see, oh it's a bird.
저는 실제로 그것이 무엇이 될 지 모릅니다. 하지만 이제 우리는 이것이 새라는 것을 알 수 있죠.
And, you find the nearest neighbors, oh,
그리고 여러분은 가장 가까운 이웃을 찾습니다.
birds and they'll all similar kind of poses.
새들말이죠. 그리고 그것들은 모두 비슷한 포즈를 취하고 있죠.
And I know that this is kind of a Ostrich heads and thses other kinds of birds.
그리고 저는 이것이 일종의 타조의 머리와 같다는 것 그리고 다른 종류의 새라는 것을 압니다.
But, they're all birds, which is pretty cool and
하지만 그것들은 모두 새들이죠. 이것은 꽤 멋지고
remember we're just using those deep features.
우리는 그저 이 깊은 특성들을 사용하고 있다는 것을 기억하세요.
And now for the last one, so show_neighbors and
이제 마지막 것을 위해 show_neighbors를 입력하고
you can play with all of this at home.
여러분은 집에서 이 모든 것들을 가지고 실험해볼 수 있습니다.
Let's show neighbors of image 2,000.
이미지 2,000의 show neighbors를 해봅시다.
Oops, Shift+Enter and what are the neighbors of image 2000?
윱스, 쉬프트+엔터 그리고 이미지 2000의 neighbors는 무엇인가요?
Okay, you have a car.
여러분은 자동차를 가졌습니다.
It got confused.
이것은 혼란에 빠졌죠.
It got an ostrich but the the rest were all cars.
이것은 타조를 가졌지만 나머지들은 모두 자동차였습니다.
So simple pictures work quite well at image retrieval.
따라서 단순한 그림들은 이미지 검색에서 꽤 잘 적용됩니다.
You saw I made one mistake in the few examples that we tried.
여러분은 제가 우리가 시도했던 일부 예제에서 저지른 실수를 보셨을겁니다.
But it actually gives you really good results and really nice performance.
하지만 이것은 실제로 여러분에게 매우 좋은 결과를 보여주었죠.
And it was never trained on this dataset, on this images.
그리거 이것은 이 데이터시트, 이미지에서 학습된 적이 없습니다.
The images were different sizes, different categories, but
이미지들은 각기 사이즈가 달랐고 카테고리가 달랐습니다. 하지만
it still worked quite well and quite exciting.
이것은 여전히 잘 작동되었습니다.
So these are tools and
따라서 이것들은 매우 광범위하게 재미있는 방법으로 사용될 수 있는
techniques that can be used in a wide range of areas in a really exciting way.
도구들이며 기술들입니다.
[MUSIC]
[음악]